{
    "time": 30,
    "maxQuestions": 50,
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Who invented C++?",
            "options": [
                "Ronaldo and Messi",
                "Haskell",
                "Ray Ban",
                "John Stroustrup",
                "Bjarne Stroustrup",
                "Alan Turing"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Bjarne Stroustrup"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is not a characteristic of OOP?",
            "options": [
                "Encapsulation",
                "Polymorphism",
                "Inheritance",
                "Togetherness"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Togetherness"
        },
        {
            "question": "A sequence of instructions written to perform a specified task on a computer is called __________",
            "options": [
                "Software",
                "Hardware",
                "Gadget",
                "Instructions"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Software"
        },
        {
            "question": "There are currently __________ generations of computer programming languages.",
            "options": [
                "Four",
                "Five",
                "Three",
                "Six"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Five"
        },
        {
            "question": "1GL is synonymous with __________",
            "options": [
                "First General Language",
                "1st Gathering in Lamingo",
                "First Grand Language",
                "First Generation Language"
            ],
            "correctOption": "First Generation Language"
        },
        {
            "question": "Fifth generation languages are currently being used for __________",
            "options": [
                "Databases",
                "Interpreters",
                "Neural Networks",
                "Batteries"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Neural Networks"
        },
        {
            "question": "For this course the language of study is an example of __________ generation programming language.",
            "options": [
                "Third",
                "Second",
                "Fourth",
                "First"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Third"
        },
        {
            "question": "__________ Programming models software in terms similar to real world objects.",
            "options": [
                "Hardware",
                "Structured",
                "Software",
                "Object Oriented"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Object Oriented"
        },
        {
            "question": "Structured Programming existed before Object Oriented Programming.",
            "options": [
                "False",
                "Maybe",
                "True",
                "None of these"
            ],
            "correctOption": "True"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is a feature of Object Oriented Programming?",
            "options": [
                "Classes",
                "Inheritance",
                "Polymorphism",
                "All of the above"
            ],
            "correctOption": "All of the above"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which is not a control structure in structured programming?",
            "options": [
                "Processor",
                "Repetition",
                "Selection",
                "Sequence"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Processor"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the program codes matches the second generation programming language?",
            "options": [
                "MUL X,Y",
                "10000001101",
                "A = SEC + GEN",
                "SELECT * FROM student;"
            ],
            "correctOption": "MUL X,Y"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the program codes matches the first generation programming language?",
            "options": [
                "MUL X,Y",
                "10000001101",
                "A = SEC + GEN",
                "SELECT * FROM student;"
            ],
            "correctOption": "10000001101"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the program codes matches the third generation programming language?",
            "options": [
                "MUL X,Y",
                "10000001101",
                "A = SEC + GEN",
                "SELECT * FROM student;"
            ],
            "correctOption": "A = SEC + GEN"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the program codes matches the fourth generation programming language?",
            "options": [
                "MUL X,Y",
                "10000001101",
                "A = SEC + GEN",
                "SELECT * FROM student;"
            ],
            "correctOption": "SELECT * FROM student;"
        },
        {
            "question": "SQL is an example of __________ generation language.",
            "options": [
                "First",
                "Second",
                "Third",
                "Fourth"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Fourth"
        },
        {
            "question": "Structured programs can be written in terms of three types of control structures except__________",
            "options": [
                "Repetition",
                "Sequence",
                "Selection",
                "Manipulation"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Manipulation"
        },
        {
            "question": "The __________ selection statement is used to execute one action when a condition is true and a different action when that condition is false.",
            "options": [
                "If",
                "If else",
                "Switch",
                "For else"
            ],
            "correctOption": "If else"
        },
        {
            "question": "What additional features did C++ add to C?",
            "options": [
                "Structured Programming",
                "Object Oriented Programming Disabilities",
                "Plusplus",
                "Object Oriented Programming Capabilities"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Object Oriented Programming Capabilities"
        },
        {
            "question": "What additional feature did C++ add to C?",
            "options": [
                "Standard Books",
                "Standard cout",
                "Standard Libraries",
                "Loops"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Standard Libraries"
        },
        {
            "question": "What are the parts of a C++ program?",
            "options": [
                "First and Last parts",
                "Structured and Unstructured parts",
                "Directive and main program",
                "Director and Personal Assistance"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Directive and main program"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is a valid name for an identifier?",
            "options": [
                "Miles",
                "3Musketeers",
                "The space",
                "Three%ofFifty"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Miles"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is an invalid identifier?",
            "options": [
                "Miles",
                "Root—of—2",
                "Root_of_2",
                "Erase"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Root—of—2"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is an invalid identifier?",
            "options": [
                "The space",
                "Nospace",
                "Correct",
                "Verycorrect"
            ],
            "correctOption": "The space"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is an invalid identifier?",
            "options": [
                "3Musketeers",
                "Musketeers3",
                "M3usketeers",
                "_Musketeers"
            ],
            "correctOption": "3Musketeers"
        },
        {
            "question": "__________ control structure execute steps or statements in the order they appear.",
            "options": [
                "Selection",
                "Sequence",
                "Repetition",
                "Manipulation"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Sequence"
        },
        {
            "question": "__________ is a one path choice selection statement.",
            "options": [
                "If",
                "If else",
                "Where else",
                "Switch"
            ],
            "correctOption": "If"
        },
        {
            "question": "__________ is a multiple path choice selection statement.",
            "options": [
                "If",
                "Where else",
                "Switch"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Switch"
        },
        {
            "question": "C++ evolved from the __________ programming language.",
            "options": [
                "A",
                "B",
                "C",
                "D"
            ],
            "correctOption": "C"
        },
        {
            "question": "C programming language evolved from __________",
            "options": [
                "BCPL and B",
                "BPPL and B",
                "BCPL and BC",
                "B"
            ],
            "correctOption": "BCPL and B"
        },
        {
            "question": "Complete this statement: C++ was developed by __________",
            "options": [
                "Bjarne Stroustrup in the 1980s and Standardized in 1998",
                "Bjarne Stroustrup in the 1980s and Standardized in 1988",
                "Bjarne Stroustrup in the 1970s and Standardized in 1998",
                "James Stroustrup in the 1980s and Standardized in 1998"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Bjarne Stroustrup in the 1980s and Standardized in 1998"
        },
        {
            "question": "C++ Directives includes the following except __________",
            "options": [
                "#include",
                "#define",
                "Comment",
                "Statements"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Statements"
        },
        {
            "question": "Single line commenting is made by using __________",
            "options": [
                "Single slash (/)",
                "Slash and an asterisk (/*)",
                "Asterisk and an slash (*/)",
                "Double slash (//)"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Double slash (//)"
        },
        {
            "question": "Multiple lines commenting is made by using __________",
            "options": [
                "Single slash (/)",
                "Triple slash (///)",
                "Slashes and an asterisks (/* */)",
                "Double slash (//)"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Slashes and an asterisks (/* */)"
        },
        {
            "question": "A __________ represents the set of values that a variable may accept or assume during program execution.",
            "options": [
                "Literal",
                "Comment",
                "Variable",
                "Data type"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Data type"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is not an importance of datatypes?",
            "options": [
                "Indicate the permissible operations for a variable",
                "Indicate the amount of memory allocated to it",
                "Indicate the range of values a variable can take",
                "Indicate the number of variables to declare"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Indicate the number of variables to declare"
        },
        {
            "question": "C++ is a __________ language.",
            "options": [
                "Untyped",
                "Typed",
                "Strict",
                "Hard"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Typed"
        },
        {
            "question": "Data in C++ either falls into or is made up of the following basic or simple categories except __________",
            "options": [
                "Floating Point Numbers",
                "Integers",
                "String",
                "Boolean"
            ],
            "correctOption": "String"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is not a kind of integer?",
            "options": [
                "Int",
                "Double",
                "Long",
                "Short"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Double"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is not a type of floating point number?",
            "options": [
                "Long double",
                "Long",
                "Double",
                "Float"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Long"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is not an integer literal?",
            "options": [
                "Decimal Number",
                "Octal Number",
                "Hexadecimal Number",
                "Exponential"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Exponential"
        },
        {
            "question": "String literals must be enclosed in __________",
            "options": [
                "Double quotes",
                "Triple slash",
                "Single slash",
                "Double slash"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Double quotes"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the % operator called?",
            "options": [
                "Percent",
                "Modulo",
                "Div",
                "Exponentiation"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Modulo"
        },
        {
            "question": "Evaluate 3 != 2",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False",
                "Yes",
                "No"
            ],
            "correctOption": "True"
        },
        {
            "question": "Evaluate (a*b >= c); If a=2, b=3 and c=6 ",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False",
                "Yes",
                "No"
            ],
            "correctOption": "True"
        },
        {
            "question": "Evaluate 7==5+2 ? 4 : 3",
            "options": [
                "7",
                "5",
                "3",
                "4"
            ],
            "correctOption": "4"
        },
        {
            "question": "Evaluate abs(­8.76)",
            "options": [
                "8.8",
                "8.76",
                "8.77",
                "­8.76"
            ],
            "correctOption": "8.76"
        },
        {
            "question": "Evaluate (!((14/3) <= 4)) && (25 > (6*5))",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False",
                "Yes",
                "84"
            ],
            "correctOption": "False"
        },
        {
            "question": "Evaluate (2 % 3)",
            "options": [
                "1",
                "2",
                "3",
                "0"
            ],
            "correctOption": "2"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does (\\n) represent in C++?",
            "options": [
                "Old line",
                "Back space",
                "New line",
                "Tab"
            ],
            "correctOption": "New line"
        },
        {
            "question": "Give the output of the statements below. int x = 10000; cout << left << setw(10) << setfill(@) << x << endl;",
            "options": [
                "10000@@@@@",
                "@@@@@10000",
                "10000",
                "@@@@@"
            ],
            "correctOption": "10000@@@@@"
        },
        {
            "question": "Structured Programming existed before Object Oriented Programming.",
            "options": [
                "False",
                "Maybe",
                "True",
                "None of these"
            ],
            "correctOption": "True"
        },
        {
            "question": "The __________ selection statement is used to execute one action when a condition is true or a different action when that condition is false.",
            "options": [
                "If",
                "If else",
                "Switch",
                "For else"
            ],
            "correctOption": "If else"
        },
        {
            "question": "C++ was developed by __________ in the __________ and Standardized in __________",
            "options": [
                "Bjarne Stroustrup in the 1980s and Standardized in 1998",
                "Bjarne Stroustrup in the 1980s and Standardized in 1988",
                "Bjarne Stroustrup in the 1970s and Standardized in 1998",
                "James Stroustrup in the 1980s and Standardized in 1998"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Bjarne Stroustrup in the 1980s and Standardized in 1998"
        },
        {
            "question": "Multiple lines commenting is made by using __________",
            "options": [
                "Single slash (/)",
                "Triple slash(///)",
                "Slashes and an asterisks (/* */)",
                "Double slash (//)"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Slashes and an asterisks (/* */)"
        },
        {
            "question": "Evaluate (3!= 2)",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False",
                "Yes",
                "No"
            ],
            "correctOption": "True"
        },
        {
            "question": "If a=4, b=3 and c=6, Evaluate (a*b >= c)",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False",
                "Yes",
                "No"
            ],
            "correctOption": "True"
        },
        {
            "question": "Evaluate (!((14/3) <= 4)) && (25 > (6*5))",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False",
                "Yes",
                "84"
            ],
            "correctOption": "False"
        },
        {
            "question": "Lvalue means __________",
            "options": [
                "left value",
                "locator value",
                "leftmost value"
            ],
            "correctOption": "locator value"
        },
        {
            "question": "Rvalue means __________",
            "options": [
                "right value",
                "real value",
                "rightmost value"
            ],
            "correctOption": "real value"
        },
        {
            "question": "__________ is also known as the lvalue",
            "options": [
                "image value",
                "colour value",
                "data value",
                "address value"
            ],
            "correctOption": "address value"
        },
        {
            "question": "__________ is also called the rvalue",
            "options": [
                "integer value",
                "colour value",
                "data value",
                "address value"
            ],
            "correctOption": "data value"
        },
        {
            "question": "__________ are used in C++ to access memory and to manipulate address.",
            "options": [
                "variable",
                "pointers",
                "identifier",
                "flash"
            ],
            "correctOption": "pointers"
        },
        {
            "question": "in C++ If v is a named variable, then &v is its __________",
            "options": [
                "data",
                "value",
                "address",
                "color"
            ],
            "correctOption": "address"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is the syntax for declaring pointer variables.",
            "options": [
                "datatype* variablename;",
                "variablename* datatype ;",
                "datatype Identifier",
                "returntype identifier"
            ],
            "correctOption": "datatype* variablename;"
        },
        {
            "question": "__________ is the inverse of & in the context of pointers",
            "options": [
                "/",
                "­^",
                "+",
                "*"
            ],
            "correctOption": "*"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is not needed in order to call by reference using pointers.",
            "options": [
                "Declare a pointer in the function header",
                "Declare receiving variable",
                "Use the dereference pointer in the function body",
                "Pass an address as an argument when the function is called."
            ],
            "correctOption": "Declare receiving variable"
        },
        {
            "question": "__________ functions calls itself as part of its definition.",
            "options": [
                "Recursive",
                "Main",
                "Common",
                "None of these"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Recursive"
        },
        {
            "question": "Base and recursive parts are the two main parts of which function?",
            "options": [
                "Main",
                "Return",
                "Common",
                "Recursive"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Recursive"
        },
        {
            "question": "Fibonacci Series, Greatest Common Divisor (GCD) and Geometric Series can be programmed with the application of __________ function",
            "options": [
                "int Main",
                "anyhow",
                "recursive",
                "common"
            ],
            "correctOption": "recursive"
        },
        {
            "question": "An array name is an address or a pointer value.",
            "options": [
                "None of the options",
                "False",
                "True",
                "Maybe"
            ],
            "correctOption": "True"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the separation of the essential qualities of an object from the details of how it works or is composed?",
            "options": [
                "Subtraction",
                "Addition",
                "Extraction",
                "Abstraction"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Abstraction"
        },
        {
            "question": "__________ and __________ are used to define Abstract data types in C++.",
            "options": [
                "pointers and variables",
                "Structures and classes",
                "identifiers and datatypes",
                "images and colours"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Structures and classes"
        },
        {
            "question": "Structures does not allow the programmer to aggregate components into a single name.",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False",
                "Maybe",
                "None of these"
            ],
            "correctOption": "False"
        },
        {
            "question": "__________ is used to access members of the structure types.",
            "options": [
                "member access operator (.)",
                "outsider access operator (*)",
                "referencer",
                "modifier"
            ],
            "correctOption": "member access operator (.)"
        },
        {
            "question": "Member Selection (—>) Operator is used to access members of a structure if a pointer variable is assigned the address of a structure.",
            "options": [
                "Why?",
                "False",
                "True",
                "How?"
            ],
            "correctOption": "True"
        },
        {
            "question": "__________ can hold both data and functions.",
            "options": [
                "Pointers",
                "Classes",
                "Variables",
                "Arrays"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Classes"
        },
        {
            "question": "An Instance of a class is called a(n)__________",
            "options": [
                "Subject",
                "Value",
                "Object",
                "Particles"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Object"
        },
        {
            "question": "private members are accessible from anywhere where the object is visible.",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False",
                "Maybe",
                "Why?"
            ],
            "correctOption": "False"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is not an access specifier?",
            "options": [
                "Private",
                "Public",
                "Social",
                "Protected"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Social"
        },
        {
            "question": "Data and functions are both members of the object.",
            "options": [
                "False",
                "True",
                "Maybe",
                "None of these"
            ],
            "correctOption": "True"
        },
        {
            "question": "A function that is used to give initial values to all attributes of a class is called a __________",
            "options": [
                "Menu",
                "Submenu",
                "Constructor",
                "Builder"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Constructor"
        },
        {
            "question": "What kind of function has the same name as it Class?",
            "options": [
                "Main",
                "public",
                "protected",
                "constructor"
            ],
            "correctOption": "constructor"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following function should have a non void return type.",
            "options": [
                "Modifiers",
                "Accessors",
                "Modifiers and Accessors",
                "None of these"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Accessors"
        },
        {
            "question": "__________ describes grouping related data and functions together as objects and defining an interface to those objects.",
            "options": [
                "Polymorphism",
                "Encapsulation",
                "Class",
                "Inheritance"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Encapsulation"
        },
        {
            "question": "__________ involves allowing code to be reused between related classes.",
            "options": [
                "Polymorphism",
                "Encapsulation",
                "Class",
                "Inheritance"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Inheritance"
        },
        {
            "question": "In defining derived classes, we only need to specify what’s different about them from their base classes. This powerful technique is called __________",
            "options": [
                "Programming by difference",
                "Programming with style",
                "Programming by addition",
                "Programming with Joy"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Programming by difference"
        },
        {
            "question": "__________ involves allowing a value to be one of several types, and determining at runtime which functions to call on it based on its type.",
            "options": [
                "Polymorphism",
                "Encapsulation",
                "Class",
                "Inheritance"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Polymorphism"
        },
        {
            "question": "What generation of programming language does this statement belong?\nstudentName = FirstName + LastName;",
            "options": [
                "1GL",
                "2GL",
                "3GL",
                "4GL"
            ],
            "correctOption": "3GL"
        },
        {
            "question": "What generation of programming language does this statement belong?\nSELECT * FROM studentTb WHERE age = 13 and height > 4.0;",
            "options": [
                "1GL",
                "2GL",
                "3GL",
                "4GL"
            ],
            "correctOption": "4GL"
        },
        {
            "question": "What generation of programming language does this statement belong?\nSUB X, Y",
            "options": [
                "1GL",
                "2GL",
                "3GL",
                "4GL"
            ],
            "correctOption": "2GL"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is not an Integer literal?",
            "options": [
                "decimal",
                "hexadecimal",
                "short",
                "octal"
            ],
            "correctOption": "short"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the most appropriate data type for 'b'",
            "options": [
                "String",
                "Integer",
                "Character",
                "Boolean"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Character"
        },
        {
            "question": "The syntax below depicts __________ Data_type identifier = data_value in C++",
            "options": [
                "Initialization of array",
                "Initialization of variables",
                "Initialization of numbers",
                "Initialization of pointer"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Initialization of variables"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the result of the following expression? 3%3",
            "options": [
                "0",
                "1",
                "2",
                "3"
            ],
            "correctOption": "0"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the result of the following expression?\n4 + 3*(4%5)",
            "options": [
                "4",
                "12",
                "0",
                "16"
            ],
            "correctOption": "16"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the result of the following C++ expression?\nstring s = sin(0.0) == 0 ? \"yes\":\"no\"; cout << s;",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "yes",
                "False",
                "no"
            ],
            "correctOption": "yes"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the result of the following C++ expression?\nstring s = ((2 * 3) + 82) % 91 > 74 && (2 * 3) < 4 ? \"yes\" : \"no\"; cout << s;",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "yes",
                "False",
                "no"
            ],
            "correctOption": "no"
        },
        {
            "question": "getch, putch and getche are functions used for __________",
            "options": [
                "String Input and Output",
                "Character Input and Output",
                "Integer printing",
                "Getting values"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Character Input and Output"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following C++ program?\n\ncout << 25 << \" in hexadecimal is: \" << hex << 25 << endl;",
            "options": [
                "25 in hexadecimal is: 11",
                "25 in hexadecimal is: 12",
                "25 in hexadecimal is: 17",
                "25 in hexadecimal is: 19"
            ],
            "correctOption": "25 in hexadecimal is: 19"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following C++ program?\n\nint a = ceil(24.7);\ncout << hex << a << endl;",
            "options": [
                "12",
                "13",
                "19",
                "29"
            ],
            "correctOption": "19"
        },
        {
            "question": "What will be the output of the statements?\ncout << setbase(16) << 25;",
            "options": [
                "12",
                "19",
                "4",
                "29"
            ],
            "correctOption": "19"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following C++ program?\n\ncout << setw(10) << setfill('_') << 12345 << endl;",
            "options": [
                "12345",
                "12345_____",
                "None of these",
                "Maybe"
            ],
            "correctOption": "12345_____"
        },
        {
            "question": "The test expression of an if statement should evaluate to a __________ value.",
            "options": [
                "Float",
                "Integer",
                "Boolean",
                "String"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Boolean"
        },
        {
            "question": "what term best describes an If statement placed inside another if statement?",
            "options": [
                "Nested If",
                "Nurtured If",
                "Steady If",
                "Deep If",
                "Two Step If",
                "Operative If"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Nested If"
        },
        {
            "question": "The switch default statement is equivalent to the __________ in if statement.",
            "options": [
                "else",
                "if else",
                "Maybe",
                "None of these"
            ],
            "correctOption": "else"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which type is best suited to represent the logical values?",
            "options": [
                "integer",
                "boolean",
                "character",
                "all of the above"
            ],
            "correctOption": "boolean"
        },
        {
            "question": "Identify the user defined types from the following?\n",
            "options": [
                "enumeration",
                "classes",
                "both enumeration and classes",
                "int"
            ],
            "correctOption": "both enumeration and classes"
        },
        {
            "question": "The value 132.54 can represented using which data type?",
            "options": [
                "double",
                "void",
                "int",
                "bool",
                "long",
                "char"
            ],
            "correctOption": "double"
        },
        {
            "question": "Pick the odd one out",
            "options": [
                "integer, characters, booleans, floats",
                "enumerations, classes",
                "integers, enums, void",
                "arrays, pointers, classes"
            ],
            "correctOption": "arrays, pointers, classes"
        },
        {
            "question": "Pick the odd one out",
            "options": [
                "array type",
                "character type",
                "boolean type ",
                "integer type"
            ],
            "correctOption": "array type"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following C++ program?\n\n    #include <iostream>\n    using namespace std;\n    int f(int p, int q)\n    {\n        if (p > q)\n            return p;\n        else\n            return q;\n    }\n\n    int main()\n    {\n        int a = 5, b = 10;\n        int k;\n        bool x = true;\n        bool y = f(a, b);\n        k =((a * b) + (x + y));\n        cout << k;\n    }",
            "options": [
                "55",
                "62",
                "52",
                "none of the above"
            ],
            "correctOption": "52"
        },
        {
            "question": "Evaluate the following\n\n(false && true) || false || true",
            "options": [
                "0",
                "1",
                "false",
                "none of the above"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1"
        },
        {
            "question": "The operator used for dereferencing or indirection is __________",
            "options": [
                "*",
                "&",
                "—>>",
                "<<—"
            ],
            "correctOption": "*"
        },
        {
            "question": "Choose the right option\n    string *x, y;",
            "options": [
                "x is a pointer to a string, y is a string",
                "y is a pointer to a string, x is a string",
                "both x and y are pointer to string types",
                "none of the mentioned"
            ],
            "correctOption": "x is a pointer to a string, y is a string"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is illegal?",
            "options": [
                "int *ip;",
                "string s, *sp = 0;",
                "int i; double* dp = &i;",
                "int *pi = 0;"
            ],
            "correctOption": "int i; double* dp = &i;"
        },
        {
            "question": "What will happen in this code?\n int a = 100, b = 200;\n    int *p = &a, *q = &b;\n    p = q;",
            "options": [
                "b is assigned to a",
                "p now points to b",
                "a is assigned to b ",
                "q now points to a"
            ],
            "correctOption": "p now points to b"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of this program?\n\n    #include <iostream>\n    using namespace std;\n\n    int main()\n    {\n        char *ptr;\n        char Str[] = \"abcdefg\";\n        ptr = Str;\n        ptr += 5;\n        cout << ptr;\n        return 0;\n    }",
            "options": [
                "fg",
                "cdef",
                "defg",
                "abcd"
            ],
            "correctOption": "fg"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following correctly declares an array?",
            "options": [
                "int array[10];",
                "int array;",
                "array{10};",
                "array array[10];"
            ],
            "correctOption": "int array[10];"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the index number of the last element of an array with 9 elements?",
            "options": [
                "9",
                "8",
                "0",
                "programmer difined"
            ],
            "correctOption": "8"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is a array?",
            "options": [
                "An array is a series of elements of the same type in contiguous memory locations ",
                "An array is a series of element ",
                "An array is a series of elements of the same type placed in non contiguous memory locations ",
                "None of the mentioned"
            ],
            "correctOption": "An array is a series of elements of the same type in contiguous memory locations "
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following accesses the seventh element stored in array?",
            "options": [
                "array[6];",
                "array[7];",
                "array(7);",
                "array;"
            ],
            "correctOption": "array[6];"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following gives the memory address of the first element in array?",
            "options": [
                "array[0];",
                "array[1];",
                "array(2);",
                "array;"
            ],
            "correctOption": "array;"
        },
        {
            "question": "Arrays in Python and C++ are _________ indexed",
            "options": [
                "0",
                "1",
                "dual"
            ],
            "correctOption": "0"
        },
        {
            "question": "Arrays in Python and C++ are zero indexed",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "True"
        },
        {
            "question": "What will be the output of this program?\n  #include <iostream>\n    using namespace std;\n    int array1[] = {1200, 200, 2300, 1230, 1543};\n    int array2[] = {12, 14, 16, 18, 20};\n    int temp, result = 0;\n\n    int main()\n    {\n        for (temp = 0; temp < 5; temp++) {\n            result += array1[temp];\n        }\n        for (temp = 0; temp < 4; temp++) {\n            result += array2[temp];\n        }\n        cout << result;\n        return 0;\n    }",
            "options": [
                "6553 ",
                "6533",
                "6522 ",
                "12200"
            ],
            "correctOption": "6533"
        },
        {
            "question": "What will be the output of the this program?\n\n    #include <iostream>\n    using namespace std;\n\n    int main ()\n    {\n        int array[] = {0, 2, 4, 6, 7, 5, 3};\n        int n, result = 0;\n        for (n = 0; n < 8; n++) {\n            result += array[n];\n        }\n        cout << result;\n        return 0;\n    }",
            "options": [
                "25",
                "26",
                "27",
                "None of the mentioned"
            ],
            "correctOption": "None of the mentioned"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of this program?\n\n    #include <stdio.h>\n    using namespace std;\n\n    int main()\n    {\n        int a = 5, b = 10, c = 15;\n        int arr[3] = {&a, &b, &c};\n        cout << *arr[*arr[1] - 8];\n        return 0;\n    }",
            "options": [
                "15",
                "18",
                "garbage value",
                "compile time error"
            ],
            "correctOption": "compile time error"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of this program?\n\n    #include <iostream>\n    using namespace std;\n\n    int main()\n    {\n        char str[5] = \"ABC\";\n        cout << str[3];\n        cout << str;\n        return 0;\n    }",
            "options": [
                "ABC",
                "ABCD ",
                "AB ",
                "None of the mentioned"
            ],
            "correctOption": "ABC"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of this program?\n\n    #include <iostream>\n    using namespace std;\n\n    int main()\n    {\n        int array[] = {10, 20, 30};\n        cout << -2[array];\n        return 0;\n    }",
            "options": [
                "-15 ",
                "-30 ",
                "compile time error",
                "garbage value"
            ],
            "correctOption": "-30 "
        },
        {
            "question": "Where does the execution of a C++ program start?",
            "options": [
                "user defined function",
                "main function ",
                "void function ",
                "none of the mentioned"
            ],
            "correctOption": "main function "
        },
        {
            "question": "Which is more effective while calling the functions?",
            "options": [
                "call by value ",
                "call by reference",
                "call by pointer ",
                "none of the mentioned"
            ],
            "correctOption": "call by reference"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of this program?\n\n    #include <iostream>\n    using namespace std;\n    void mani()\n    void mani()\n    {\n        cout << \"hai\";\n    }\n\n    int main()\n    {\n        mani();\n        return 0;\n    }",
            "options": [
                "hai ",
                "haihai ",
                "compile time error ",
                "none of the mentioned"
            ],
            "correctOption": "compile time error "
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of this program?\n\n    #include <iostream>\n    using namespace std;\n    void fun(int x, int y)\n    {\n        x = 20;\n        y = 10;\n    }\n\n    int main()\n    {\n        int x = 10;\n        fun(x, x);\n        cout << x;\n        return 0;\n    }",
            "options": [
                "10",
                "20 ",
                "compile time error ",
                "none of the mentioned"
            ],
            "correctOption": "10"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the scope of the variable declared in the user definied function?",
            "options": [
                "whole program",
                "only inside the function block",
                "none of the mentioned"
            ],
            "correctOption": "only inside the function block"
        },
        {
            "question": "What's the minimum number of functions needed in a C++ program?",
            "options": [
                "0",
                "1",
                "2",
                "3"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of this program?\n\n    #include <iostream>\n    using namespace std;\n\n    int main()\n    {\n     cout << \"5 + 5\";\n      return 0;\n    }\n   ",
            "options": [
                "10",
                "5 + 5",
                "55",
                "Error"
            ],
            "correctOption": "5 + 5"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of this program?\n\n    #include <iostream>\n    using namespace std;\n\n    int main()\n    {\n     cout << \"5 + 5\";\n    }\n   ",
            "options": [
                "10",
                "5 + 5",
                "55",
                "Error"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Error"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of this program?\n\n    #include <iostream>\n    using namespace std;\n\n    int main()\n    {\n     string prince = \"vera\";\n     cout << \"vince\";\n      return 0;\n    }\n   ",
            "options": [
                "vera",
                "vince",
                "vera prince",
                "Error"
            ],
            "correctOption": "vince"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of this program?\n\n    #include <iostream>\n    using namespace std;\n\n    int main()\n    {\n     //cout << \"5 + 5\";\n      return 0;\n    }\n   ",
            "options": [
                "5 + 5",
                "55",
                "10",
                "none of the above"
            ],
            "correctOption": "none of the above"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of the following program?\n\n#include<iostream>\nusing namespace std;\n\nmain () { \n   float t = 2;\n\t\n\tswitch(t) {\n      case 2: cout << 'Hi';\n\t\tdefault: cout << \"Hello\";\n\t}\n}",
            "options": [
                "Hi",
                "Hello",
                "HiHello",
                "Error"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Error"
        },
        {
            "question": "A single line comment in C++ language source code can begin with __________\n",
            "options": [
                ";",
                ":",
                "/*",
                "//"
            ],
            "correctOption": "//"
        },
        {
            "question": "All of these are features of Object Oriented Programming (OOP) EXCEPT",
            "options": [
                "class",
                "parent",
                "inheritance",
                "polymorphism"
            ],
            "correctOption": "parent"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is not a form of control in structured programing?",
            "options": [
                "series",
                "sequence",
                "selection",
                "repetition"
            ],
            "correctOption": "series"
        },
        {
            "question": "What's the output of this code?\n\n#include <iostream>\nusing std::cout;\nusing std::cin;\n\nint main(){\ncout << 2 + 2 << endl;\nreturn 0;\n}",
            "options": [
                "2 + 2",
                "4",
                "2 + 2=4",
                "Error"
            ],
            "correctOption": "4"
        },
        {
            "question": "Select the wrong identifier",
            "options": [
                "int",
                "integer",
                "identifier",
                "wrong"
            ],
            "correctOption": "int"
        },
        {
            "question": "What's the output of the following lines of code.\n#include <iostream>\nusing namespace std;\n\nint main(){\n     for(int i =0; i<=5;i++){\n              cout << i+\",\";\n     }\n}",
            "options": [
                "0 1 2 3 4 5 ",
                "0,1,2,3,4,5,",
                "0,1,2,3,4,5",
                "0,1,2,3,4"
            ],
            "correctOption": "0,1,2,3,4,5,"
        },
        {
            "question": "What's the output of the program below.\n\n#include <iostream>\nusing namespace std;\n\nint main(){\n      int sum=0;\n      int a=5;\n      int b = 10;\n      a=b;\n      b=a;\n      sum = a+b;\n      cout << \"sum\";\n      return 0;\n}",
            "options": [
                "0",
                "10",
                "20",
                "sum"
            ],
            "correctOption": "sum"
        },
        {
            "question": "What's the output of the program below.\n\n#include <iostream>\nusing namespace std;\n\nint main(){\n      int sum=0;\n      int a=5;\n      int b = 10;\n      a=b;\n      b=a;\n      sum = a+b;\n      cout << sum;\n      return 0;\n}",
            "options": [
                "sum",
                "10",
                "20",
                "Error"
            ],
            "correctOption": "20"
        },
        {
            "question": "What's the output of the program below.\n\n#include <iostream>\nusing namespace std;\n\nint main(){\n      int sum=0;\n      int a=5;\n      int b = 10;\n      a=b;\n      b=a;\n      sum = a+b;\n      cout << \"sum\";\n      \n}",
            "options": [
                "10",
                "20",
                "sum",
                "Error"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Error"
        },
        {
            "question": "What's the output of the program below.\n\n#include <iostream>\nusing namespace std;\n\nint main(){\n       int a=5;\n      int b = 10;\n      a=b;\n      b=a;\n      sum = a+b;\n      cout << \"sum\";\n      return 0;\n}",
            "options": [
                "sum",
                "20",
                "10",
                "Error"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Error"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is not a name for a valid identifier;",
            "options": [
                "miles84",
                "3musketeers",
                "root_of_3",
                "none of the above"
            ],
            "correctOption": "3musketeers"
        },
        {
            "question": "The __________ selection statement is used to execute one action when the condition is true and another when the condition is false.",
            "options": [
                "if",
                "do while",
                "if else",
                "switch"
            ],
            "correctOption": "if else"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is not a correct directive?",
            "options": [
                "#include <stdio.h>",
                "#include <c++.y>",
                "#include <cmath>",
                "All of the these"
            ],
            "correctOption": "#include <c++.y>"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is not a correct extension for a C++ code file?",
            "options": [
                ".cc",
                ".cpp",
                ".cxx",
                ".ccc"
            ],
            "correctOption": ".ccc"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is not a correct extension for a C++ header file?",
            "options": [
                ".h",
                ".hpp",
                ".hhh"
            ],
            "correctOption": ".hhh"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is a 3rd generation statement;",
            "options": [
                "mul A D",
                "int a=8;",
                "1001101",
                "none of the above"
            ],
            "correctOption": "int a=8;"
        },
        {
            "question": "How are constants declared?",
            "options": [
                "const keyword ",
                "#define identifier",
                "either with the const keyword and or the #define identifier",
                "None of the mentioned"
            ],
            "correctOption": "either with the const keyword and or the #define identifier"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of this program?\n\n    #include <iostream>\n    using namespace std;\n\n    int main()\n    {\n        int  const  p = 5;\n        cout << ++p;\n        return 0;\n    }",
            "options": [
                "5",
                "6",
                "Error",
                "None of the options"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Error"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of this program?\n\n    #include <iostream>\n    using namespace std;\n    #define PI 3.14159\n\n    int main ()\n    {\n        float r = 2;\n        float circle;\n        circle = 2 * PI * r;\n        cout << circle;\n        return 0;\n    }\n",
            "options": [
                "12.5664",
                "13.5664",
                "10",
                "compile time error"
            ],
            "correctOption": "12.5664"
        },
        {
            "question": "Regarding following code snippet, which of the options is true?\n\nconst int a = 100;",
            "options": [
                "Declares a variable a with 100 as its initial value",
                "Declares a construction a with 100 as its initial value",
                "Declares a constant a whose value will be 100 ",
                "Constructs an integer type variable with a as identifier and 100 as value"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Declares a constant a whose value will be 100 "
        },
        {
            "question": "In a group of nested loops, which loop is executed the most number of times?",
            "options": [
                "the outermost loop",
                "the innermost loop",
                "all loops are executed the same number of times",
                "cannot be determined without knowing the size of the loops"
            ],
            "correctOption": "the innermost loop"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which looping process checks the test condition at the end of the loop",
            "options": [
                "for",
                "while",
                "do while",
                "All of the options"
            ],
            "correctOption": "do while"
        },
        {
            "question": "What's the output of the code below?\n\n#include <iostream>\n \nusing namespace std;\n\nint main () {\n \n   int    i;\n   \n   int &r = i;\n \n   i = 5;\n   \n   cout << r << endl;\n \n     return 0;\n}",
            "options": [
                "5",
                "r",
                "Error",
                "None of these"
            ],
            "correctOption": "5"
        },
        {
            "question": "Assuming that the variable declared was saved in memory location 0xbfebd5c0. What's the output of the code below?\n\n#include <iostream>\nusing namespace std;\n\nint main () {\n   int  var;\n   int  var = 20; \n   int  *ip; \n   ip = &var;   \n   cout << *ip;  \n\n   return 0;\n}",
            "options": [
                "20",
                "0xbfebd5c0",
                "&var",
                "Error"
            ],
            "correctOption": "20"
        },
        {
            "question": "Assuming that the variable declared was stored by the computer in memory location 0xbfebd5c0. What's the output of the code below?\n\n#include <iostream>\nusing namespace std;\n\nint main () {\n   int  var;\n   var=10;\n    cout << &var << endl;\n   \n}",
            "options": [
                "&var",
                "0xbfebd5c0",
                "10",
                "Error"
            ],
            "correctOption": "0xbfebd5c0"
        },
        {
            "question": "Assuming that the variable declared was stored by the computer in memory location 0xbfebd5c0. What's the output of the code below.\n\n#include <iostream>\nusing namespace std;\n\nint main () {\n   int  var;\n   var=10;\n    cout << \"&var\" << endl;\n   return 0;\n}",
            "options": [
                "&var",
                "0xbfebd5c0",
                "10",
                "Error"
            ],
            "correctOption": "&var"
        },
        {
            "question": "Assuming that the variable declared was saved in memory location 0xbfebd5c0. What's the output of the code below\n\n#include <iostream>\nusing namespace std;\n\nint main () {\n   int  var;\n   int  var = 20;\n   ip = &var;   \n   int  *ip; \n   cout << *ip;  \n\n   return 0;\n}",
            "options": [
                "20",
                "0xbfebd5c0",
                "&var",
                "Error"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Error"
        },
        {
            "question": "Assuming that the variable declared was saved in memory location 0xbfebd5c0. What's the output of the code below\n#include <iostream>\nusing namespace std;\n\nint main () {\n   int var = 20; \n   int  *ip; \n   ip = &var;   \n   cout << ip;  \n\n   return 0;\n}",
            "options": [
                "20",
                "0xbfebd5c0",
                "&var",
                "Error"
            ],
            "correctOption": "0xbfebd5c0"
        },
        {
            "question": "What's the output of the code below, assuming that the array 'var' is stored in consecutive memory address of 10001, 10002, 10003, 10004 ... ?\n\n#include <iostream>\nusing namespace std;\nconst int MAX = 3;\n\nint main () {\n   int  var[MAX] = {10, 100, 200};\n   int  *ptr;\n\n \n   ptr = var;\n   \n   for (int i = 0; i < MAX; i++) {\n      cout << \"Address of var[\" << i << \"] = \";\n      cout << ptr << endl;\n\n      cout << \"Value of var[\" << i << \"] = \";\n      cout << *ptr << endl;\n\n       ptr++;\n   }\n   \n   return 0;\n}",
            "options": [
                "Address of var[0] = 10001 \nValue of var[0] = 10\n Address of var[1] = 10002\nValue of var[1] = 100 \nAddress of var[2] = 10003 \nValue of var[2] = 200",
                "Address of var[1] = 10001 \nValue of var[1] = 10\n Address of var[2] = 10002\nValue of var[2] = 100 \nAddress of var[3] = 10003 \nValue of var[3] = 200",
                "Address of var[0] = 10001 Value of var[0] = 10\n Address of var[1] = 10002 Value of var[1] = 100 \nAddress of var[2] = 10003 Value of var[2] = 200",
                "Error"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Address of var[0] = 10001 \nValue of var[0] = 10\n Address of var[1] = 10002\nValue of var[1] = 100 \nAddress of var[2] = 10003 \nValue of var[2] = 200"
        },
        {
            "question": "What's the output of the code below.\n\n#include <iostream>\nusing namespace std;\n \nvoid swap(int& x, int& y);\n\nint main () {\n\n   int a = 100;\n   int b = 200;\n \n   cout << a+\" ' << b << endl;\n \n\n   swap(a, b);\n \n   cout << a+\" ' << b << endl;\n \n   return 0;\n}\n \n\nvoid swap(int& x, int& y) {\n\n   int temp;\n   temp = \n   x = y;    \n   y = temp; \n  \n   return;\n}",
            "options": [
                "100 200\n100 200",
                "200 100\n100 200",
                "100 200\n200 100",
                "Error"
            ],
            "correctOption": "100 200\n200 100"
        },
        {
            "question": "What's the output of the code below.\n\n#include <iostream>\nusing namespace std;\n \nvoid swap(int& x, int& y);\n\nint main () {\n\n   int a = 100;\n   int b = 200;\n \n   cout << a+\" ' << b << endl;\n \n\n   swap(a, b);\n \n   cout << a+\" ' << b << endl;\n \n   return 0;\n}\n \n\nvoid swap(int& x, int& y) {\n\n   int temp;\n   temp = \n   x = y;    \n   y = temp; \n  \n   return 0;\n}",
            "options": [
                "100 200\n100 200",
                "200 100\n100 200",
                "100 200\n200 100",
                "Error"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Error"
        },
        {
            "question": "What's the output of the code below?\n\n#include <iostream>\n \nusing namespace std;\nconst int MAX = 3;\n\nint main () {\n   int  var[MAX] = {10, 100, 200};\n   int *ptr[MAX];\n  ptr[3] = &var[2];\n  cout << *ptr[3] << endl;\n   \n   return 0;\n}",
            "options": [
                "200",
                "100",
                "10",
                "Error"
            ],
            "correctOption": "200"
        },
        {
            "question": "What's the output of the code below?\n\n#include <iostream>\n \nusing namespace std;\nconst int MAX = 3;\n\nint main () {\n   int  var[MAX] = {10, 100, 200};\n   int *ptr[MAX];\n  ptr[0] = &var[2];\n  cout << *ptr[0] << endl;\n   \n   return 0;\n}",
            "options": [
                "200",
                "100",
                "10",
                "Error"
            ],
            "correctOption": "200"
        },
        {
            "question": "What's the output of the code below?\n\n#include <iostream>\n \nusing namespace std;\nconst int MAX = 3;\n\nint main () {\n   int  var[MAX] = {10, 100, 200};\n   int *ptr[MAX];\n  ptr[1] = &var[2];\n  cout << *ptr[1] << endl;\n   \n   return 0.0;\n}",
            "options": [
                "200",
                "100",
                "10",
                "Error"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Error"
        },
        {
            "question": "What's the output of the code below?\n\n#include <iostream>\n \nusing namespace std;\nconst int MAX = 3;\n\nint main () {\n   int  var[MAX] = {10, 100, 200};\n   int *ptr[MAX];\n  ptr[1] = &var[1];\n  cout << ptr[1] << endl;\n   \n   return 0;\n}",
            "options": [
                "200",
                "the memory address of var[1]",
                "ptr[1]",
                "Error"
            ],
            "correctOption": "the memory address of var[1]"
        },
        {
            "question": "What's the output of the code below?\n\n#include <iostream>\n \nusing namespace std;\nconst int MAX = 3;\n\nint main () {\n   int  var[MAX] = {10, 100, 200};\n   int *ptr[MAX];\n  ptr[2] = &var[0];\n  cout << *ptr(2) << endl;\n   \n   return 0;\n}",
            "options": [
                "200",
                "100",
                "10",
                "Error"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Error"
        },
        {
            "question": "What's the output of the code below?\n\n#include <iostream>\n \nusing namespace std;\nconst int MAX = 3;\n\nint main () {\n   int  var[MAX] = {10, 100, 200};\n   int *ptr[MAX];\n  ptr[3] = &var[3];\n  cout << *ptr[3] << endl;\n   \n   return 0;\n}",
            "options": [
                "200",
                "100",
                "10",
                "Error"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Error"
        },
        {
            "question": "What's the output of the code below.\n#include <iostream>\nusing namespace std;\nvoid main(){\ncout << \"hello world\";\nreturn 0;\n}",
            "options": [
                "hello world",
                "helloworld",
                "Error",
                "HELLO WORLD"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Error"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following statement is correct?",
            "options": [
                "Overloaded functions must have different signatures",
                "Overloaded functions can have different names",
                "Overloaded functions cannot be recursive"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Overloaded functions must have different signatures"
        },
        {
            "question": "What's the output of the program below?\n        #include  <iostream>\n        using namespace std;\n\n        void duplicate (int& a, int& b, int& c)\n\n        {\n\n            a *= 2;\n\n            b *= 2;\n\n            c *= 2;\n\n        }\n\n        int main ()\n\n        {\n\n            int x = 1, y = 3, z = 7;\n\n            duplicate (x, y, z);\n\n            cout << x << y << z;\n\n            return 0;\n\n        }",
            "options": [
                "1468",
                "2812",
                "2614",
                "none of the mentioned"
            ],
            "correctOption": "2614"
        },
        {
            "question": "What will happen in this code?\n    int a = 100, b = 200;\n    int *p = &a, *q = &b;\n    p = q;",
            "options": [
                "b is assigned to a",
                "p now points to b",
                "a is assigned to b",
                "q now points to a"
            ],
            "correctOption": "p now points to b"
        },
        {
            "question": "Pick out the correct statement.",
            "options": [
                "Increment operator ++ adds 1 to its operand ",
                "Increment operator ++ adds 2 to its operand ",
                "Decrement operator ++ subtracts 1 to its operand",
                "None of the mentioned"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Increment operator ++ adds 1 to its operand "
        },
        {
            "question": "What's the output of the program below?\n       #include <iostream>\n\n        using namespace std;\n\n        int main()\n\n        {\n\n            int a = 21;\n\n            int c ;\n\n            c = a++;\n\n            cout << c;  \n\n            return 0;\n\n        }",
            "options": [
                "21",
                "22",
                "23",
                "20"
            ],
            "correctOption": "21"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of this program?\n\n        #include <iostream>\n\n        using namespace std;\n\n        int main()\n\n        {\n\n            int x = 5, y = 5;\n\n            cout << ++x << --y << endl;\n\n            return 0;\n\n        }",
            "options": [
                "55",
                "64",
                "46",
                "45"
            ],
            "correctOption": "64"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of this program?\n\n        #include <iostream> \n\n        using namespace std;\n\n        int main()\n\n        {\n\n            int x = 5, y = 5, z;\n\n            x = ++x; y = --y;\n\n            z = x++ + y--;\n\n            cout << z;\n\n            return 0;\n\n        }\n\n",
            "options": [
                "10",
                "11",
                "9",
                "12"
            ],
            "correctOption": "10"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of this program?\n\n        #include <iostream>  \n\n        using namespace std;\n\n        int main()\n\n        {\n\n            int x = 5, y = 5, z;\n\n            x = ++x; y = --y;\n\n            z = x + ++x;\n\n            cout << z;\n\n            return 0;\n\n        }",
            "options": [
                "11",
                "12",
                "13",
                "14"
            ],
            "correctOption": "14"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of this program?\n\n        #include <iostream> \n\n        using namespace std;\n\n        int main()\n\n        {\n\n            int num1 = 5;\n\n            int num2 = 3;\n\n            int num3 = 2;\n\n            num1 = num2++;\n\n            num2 = --num3;\n\n            cout << num1 << num2 << num3;\n\n            return 0;\n\n        }",
            "options": [
                "532 ",
                "235 ",
                "312 ",
                "311"
            ],
            "correctOption": "311"
        },
        {
            "question": "What will be the output of the this program?\n\n        #include <stdio.h>\n\n        using namespace std;\n\n        int main ()\n\n        {\n\n            int array[] = {0, 2, 4, 6, 7, 5, 3};\n\n            int n, result = 0;\n\n            for (n = 0; n < 8; n++) {\n\n                result += array[n];\n\n            }\n\n            cout << result;\n\n            return 0;\n\n        }",
            "options": [
                "25",
                "26",
                "27",
                "None of the mentioned"
            ],
            "correctOption": "None of the mentioned"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of this program?\n\n        #include <iostream>\n\n        using namespace std;\n\n        int main()\n\n        {\n\n            int  const  p = 5;\n\n            cout << ++p;\n\n            return 0;\n\n        }",
            "options": [
                "5",
                "6",
                "Error",
                "None of these"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Error"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of this program?\n\n        #include <iostream>\n\n        using namespace std;\n\n        int main()\n\n        {\n\n            int a, b;\n\n            int* c;\n\n            c = &a;\n\n            a = 200;\n\n            b = 200;\n\n            *c = 100;\n\n            b = *c;\n\n            cout << *c << \" \" << b;\n\n            return 0;\n\n        }",
            "options": [
                "100 200 ",
                "100 0 ",
                "200 200 ",
                "100 100"
            ],
            "correctOption": "100 100"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of this program?\n\n        #include <iostream>\n\n        using namespace std;\n\n        int main()\n\n        {\n\n            int x;\n\n            int *p;\n\n            x = 5;\n\n            p = &x;\n\n            cout << *p;\n\n            return 0;\n\n        }",
            "options": [
                "5",
                "10 ",
                "memory address",
                "none of the mentioned"
            ],
            "correctOption": "5"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of this program?\n\n        #include <iostream>\n\n        using namespace std;\n\n        int main() \n\n        {\n\n            int x = 9;\n\n            int* p = &x;\n\n            cout << sizeof(p);\n\n            return 0;\n\n        }",
            "options": [
                "4 ",
                "2",
                "Depends on compiler ",
                "none of the mentioned"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Depends on compiler "
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of this program?\n\n        #include <iostream>\n\n        using namespace std;\n\n        int main() \n\n        {\n\n            int x = 9;\n\n            int* p = &x;\n\n            cout << sizeof(p);\n\n            return 0;\n\n        }",
            "options": [
                "4 ",
                "2",
                "Depends on compiler ",
                "none of the mentioned"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Depends on compiler "
        },
        {
            "question": "Pick the wrong statement",
            "options": [
                "References are less powerful than pointers",
                "References are safer and easier to use",
                "Both references and pointers can be used to change local variables of one function inside another function",
                "References can be NULL"
            ],
            "correctOption": "References can be NULL"
        },
        {
            "question": "Pick the incorrect option",
            "options": [
                "Both references and pointers can be used to save copying of big objects when passed as arguments to functions or returned from functions, to get efficiency gain.",
                "Pointers can often be made NULL",
                "Once a reference is created, it can be later made to reference another object",
                "A reference must be initialized when declared"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Once a reference is created, it can be later made to reference another object"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the return value of f(p, p) if the value of p is initialized to 5 before the call? Note that the first parameter is passed by reference, whereas the second parameter is passed by value. \n\nint f(int &x, int c) {\n   c  = c - 1;\n   if (c == 0) return 1;\n   x = x + 1;\n   return f(x, c) * x;\n} ",
            "options": [
                "3024",
                "6561",
                "55440",
                "161051"
            ],
            "correctOption": "6561"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following functions must use reference.",
            "options": [
                "Assignment operator function",
                "Copy Constructor",
                "Destructor",
                "Parameterized constructor"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Copy Constructor"
        },
        {
            "question": "Predict the output of following C++ program\n\n#include<iostream>\nusing namespace std;\n \nint &fun()\n{\n    static int x = 10;\n    return x;\n}\n\nint main()\n{\n    fun() = 30;\n    cout << fun();\n    return 0;\n}",
            "options": [
                "Compiler Error: Function cannot be used as lvalue",
                "10",
                "50",
                "30"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Compiler Error: Function cannot be used as lvalue"
        },
        {
            "question": "Predict the output of following C++ program\n\n#include<iostream>\nusing namespace std;\n \nint &fun()\n{\n    int x = 10;\n    return x;\n}\n\nint main()\n{\n    fun() = 30;\n    cout << fun();\n    return 0;\n}",
            "options": [
                "May cause runtime error",
                "May cause compiler error",
                "Always works fine",
                "0"
            ],
            "correctOption": "May cause runtime error"
        },
        {
            "question": "Predict the output of following C++ program\n\n#include<iostream>\nusing namespace std;\n\nint main()\n{\n  int x = 10;\n  int& ref = x;\n  ref = 20;\n  cout << \"x = \" << x << endl ;\n  x = 30;\n  cout << \"ref = \" << ref << endl;\n  return 0;\n}",
            "options": [
                "x = 20 ref = 30",
                "x = 20 ref = 20",
                "x = 10 ref = 30",
                "x = 30 ref = 30"
            ],
            "correctOption": "x = 20 ref = 30"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the output of this program?\n\n        #include <iostream>\n\n        using namespace std;\n\n        int main() \n\n        {\n\n            int x = 9;\n\n            int* p = &x;\n\n            cout << sizeof(p);\n\n            return 0;\n\n        }",
            "options": [
                "4 ",
                "2",
                "Depends on compiler ",
                "none of the mentioned"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Depends on compiler "
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following keyword is used to declare the header file?",
            "options": [
                "include",
                "exclude",
                "string",
                "namespace"
            ],
            "correctOption": "include"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these produces a alert sound when used in a program?",
            "options": [
                "cout << \"\\n\";",
                "cout << \"\\a\";",
                "cout << \"\\f\";",
                "cout << \"\\t\";"
            ],
            "correctOption": "cout << \"\\a\";"
        },
        {
            "question": "What's the output of the code below?\n\n#include <iostream>\n#include <iomanip>\nusing namespace std;\n\nint main()\n{\nint number = 20;\ncout << dec << number << \" in octal is: \" << oct << number << endl;\nsystem(\"pause\");\nreturn 0;\n}",
            "options": [
                "20 in octal is: 24",
                "25",
                "20 in hexadecimal is: 24",
                "20 in octal is: 18",
                "24"
            ],
            "correctOption": "20 in octal is: 24"
        },
        {
            "question": "What's the output of the code below?\n\n#include <iostream>\n#include <iomanip>\nusing namespace std;\n\nint main()\n{\nint number =20 ;\ncout << dec << number << \" in octal is: \" << oct << number << endl;\nreturn 0;\n}",
            "options": [
                "20 in hexadecimal is: 14",
                "20 in octal is: 24",
                "25",
                "20 in octal is: 18",
                "20 in hexadecimal is: 24",
                "24"
            ],
            "correctOption": "20 in octal is: 24"
        },
        {
            "question": "Predict the output of following C++ program\n\n#include <iostream>\n#include <iomanip>\nusing namespace std;\n\nint main()\n{\nint number=430;\ncout << number << \" in octal is: \" << hex << number << endl;\n\nreturn 0;\n}",
            "options": [
                "115",
                "116",
                "117",
                "118"
            ],
            "correctOption": "118"
        },
        {
            "question": "Predict the output of following C++ program\n\n#include <iostream>\nusing std::cout;\nusing std::left;\nusing std::right;\n#include <iomanip>\nusing std::setfill;\nusing std::setw;\n\nint main()\n{\nint x = 10000;\ncout << left << setw( 10 ) << setfill('%') << x << endl;\n\nreturn 0;\n}",
            "options": [
                "%%%%%%%%%%10000",
                "%%%%%10000",
                "10000%%%%%",
                "Error"
            ],
            "correctOption": "10000%%%%%"
        },
        {
            "question": "Predict the output of following C++ program\n\n#include <iostream>\nusing std::cout;\nusing std::left;\nusing std::right;\n#include <iomanip>\nusing std::setfill;\nusing std::setw;\n\nint main()\n{\nint x = 10000;\ncout << right << setw(100 << setfill('@') << x << endl;\n\nreturn 0;\n}",
            "options": [
                "@@@@@10000",
                "10000@@@@@",
                "10000@@@@@",
                "Error"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Error"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following cannot be incremented?",
            "options": [
                "pointers",
                "references",
                "variables",
                "arrays"
            ],
            "correctOption": "references"
        },
        {
            "question": "if int a = 50;\nthen what is  the value of (int) a/=3; ",
            "options": [
                "15",
                "16",
                "17",
                "18"
            ],
            "correctOption": "16"
        },
        {
            "question": "What's the output of the code below?\n\n#include <iostream>\nusing namespace std;\nvoid squareByPtr ( int * numPtr ) {\n* numPtr = * numPtr * * numPtr ;\n}\n\nint main () {\nint x = 5;\nsquareByPtr (& x ) ;\ncout << x ; \nreturn 0;\n}",
            "options": [
                "24",
                "23",
                "25",
                "26"
            ],
            "correctOption": "25"
        },
        {
            "question": "What's the output of the code below?\n\n#include <iostream>\nusing namespace std;\n\nvoid squareByPtr ( int  numPtr ) {\n numPtr = numPtr *  numPtr ;\n}\n\nint main () {\nint x = 5;\nsquareByPtr (& x ) ;\ncout << x ; \n\nreturn 0;\n}",
            "options": [
                "5",
                "10",
                "25",
                "Error"
            ],
            "correctOption": "5"
        },
        {
            "question": "What's the output of the code below?\n\n#include <iostream>\nusing namespace std;\nvoid squareByPtr ( int * numPtr ) {\n* numPtr = * numPtr * * numPtr ;\n}\n\nint main () {\nint x = 5;\nsquareByPtr (& x ) ;\ncout << x ; \n\n}",
            "options": [
                "5",
                "10",
                "25",
                "Error"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Error"
        },
        {
            "question": "Neglecting all headers, what's the output of the code snippet below?\n\nint high = 20;\nint low = 0;\nwhile (low < high)\n{\nlow = low + 3;\nhigh = high - 2;\n}\ncout << \"Low: \" << low << \"\tHigh: \" << high << endl;",
            "options": [
                "Low: 12 High: 14",
                "Low: 10 High: 12",
                "Low: 12 High: 12",
                "Low: 12 High: 16"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Low: 12 High: 12"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following Contains function prototypes for stream manipulators that format streams of\ndata.",
            "options": [
                "<iostream>",
                "<iomanip>",
                "<cmath>",
                "<protype>"
            ],
            "correctOption": "<iomanip>"
        },
        {
            "question": "Functions are also known as all the following except?",
            "options": [
                "modules",
                "methods",
                "routines",
                "actions"
            ],
            "correctOption": "actions"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is not an access modifier",
            "options": [
                "internal",
                "public",
                "private",
                "protected"
            ],
            "correctOption": "internal"
        },
        {
            "question": "*ptr++ is equivalent to?",
            "options": [
                "ptr++",
                "++*ptr",
                "*ptr",
                "None of these"
            ],
            "correctOption": "None of these"
        },
        {
            "question": "cin is for ___________ while cout is for ___________",
            "options": [
                "input, output",
                "output, input",
                "None of these",
                "All of these"
            ],
            "correctOption": "input, output"
        },
        {
            "question": "scanf is for ___________ while printf is for ___________",
            "options": [
                "input, output",
                "output, input",
                "None of these",
                "All of these"
            ],
            "correctOption": "input, output"
        },
        {
            "question": "The statement scanf(\"%d\", &var);",
            "options": [
                "assigns an integer to a variable",
                "prints the value 55",
                "assings a float to a variable",
                "prints an error value"
            ],
            "correctOption": "assigns an integer to a variable"
        },
        {
            "question": "The statement printf(\"%d\", 55);",
            "options": [
                "assigns an integer to a variable",
                "prints the value 55",
                "assings a float to a variable",
                "prints an error value"
            ],
            "correctOption": "prints the value 55"
        }
    ]
}
